<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<body>
    <head style="text-transformation:uppercase">Page 4
        <lb/><title>The Soul.<seg>*</seg></title><annotation xml:id="a004">In his 1891 <em><bibl>History of the African Methodist Episcopal Church</bibl>,</em><persName>Daniel A. Payne</persName>the church's sixth bishop and its first histographer, recalls that two of <persName>Harper's</persName>poetic<bibl>"productions of 1853"</bibl>were published in the<em><bibl>Christian Recorder:</bibl></em><bibl>"The Soul"</bibl>and <bibl>"The Dying Christian"</bibl>(301-303). In addition to reproducing revised versions of each poem, <persName>Payne</persName>notes that <persName>Harper</persName>contributed essays on "Christianity" and "Womens Rights" to the <em><bibl>Christian Recorder</bibl></em>between 1852 and 1853(305)."Christianity" may be the essay of the same name that <persName>Harper</persName>printed in her 1854 <bibl><em>Poems on Miscellaneous Subjects.</em></bibl></annotation></head>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>Bring forth the balance, let the weights be gold,</l>
            <l>We'd know the worth of a deathless soul;</l>
            <l>Bring rubies and jems from every mine,</l>
            <l>With the wealth of the ocean, land and clime.</l>           
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>Bring the joys of the glad green <placeName>earth</placeName>,</l>
            <l>Its playful simles and careless mirth;</l>
            <l>The dews of youth, and flushes of health,</l>
            <l>Bring! Oh Bring! the wide world's wealth</l>
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>Bring the rich and radiant gems of thought</l>
            <l>From the mines and deeps of knowledge brought;</l>
            <l>Bring glowing words and ponderous lore</l>
            <l>Search <placeName>heaven</placeName> and <placeName>earth's</placeName> arcana<annotation xml:id="a005">arcana: secrets or mysteries</annotation> o'er<expan>over</expan> </l>
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>Bring the fairest, brightest rolls of fame,</l>
            <l>Unwritten with a deed of guilt or shame;</l>
            <l>Bring honor's guerdon,<annotation xml:id="a006">guerdon: reward</annotation> and victory's crown,</l>
            <l>Robes of pride, and laurels of renown.</l>
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>We've brought the wealth of every mine,</l>
            <l>We've ransack'd<expan>ransacked</expan> ocean, land clime,</l>
            <l>And caught the joyous smiles away</l>
            <l>From the prattling babe to the sire grey.</l>
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>We've brought the names of the noble dead</l>
            <l>With those who in their footsteps tread;</l>
            <l>Here are wreaths of pride and gems of thought</l>
            <l>From the battle field and study brought.</l>
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>Heap high the gems, pile up the gold,</l>
            <l>Heavy's the weight of a deathless soul;</l>
            <l>Make room for all the wealth of <placeName>earth</placeName></l>
            <l>Its honors, joys, and careless mirth.</l>
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>Leave me a niche for the rolls of fame</l>
            <l>For precious indeed is a spotless name,</l>
            <l>For the wreaths, the robes and gems of thought,</l>
            <l>Let an empty place in the scale be sought.</l>
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <pb/><head style="text-transform:uppercase">Page 5</head>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>With care we've adjusted balance and scale</l>
            <l>Futile our efforts we've seen them fail;</l>
            <l>Lighter than dust is the wealth of <placeName>earth</placeName></l>
            <l>Weigh'd<expan>Weighed</expan>in the scales with immortal worth</l>
        </lg>
        <lb/>
        <lg>
            <l>Could we drag the sun from its golden car<annotation xml:id="a007">car:chariot</annotation></l>
            <l>To lay in this balance with ev'ry<expan>every</expan> star,</l>
            <l>T'would<expan>It would</expan> darken the day and obscure the night,</l>
            <l>But the weight of the balance would still be light.</l>
        </lg>
</body>